<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Culbert Report</title><subtitle>I like writing into the void</subtitle> <updated>2026-02-23T16:53:42+00:00</updated> <author> <name>Matt Culbert</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2026 Matt Culbert </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>We Have Lost The Plot With Llms</title><link href="/posts/We-have-lost-the-plot-with-LLMs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Have Lost The Plot With Llms" /><published>2026-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2026-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/We-have-lost-the-plot-with-LLMs/</id> <content src="/posts/We-have-lost-the-plot-with-LLMs/" /> <author> <name>Matt Culbert</name> </author> <summary> We’ve collectively lost the plot In IT and security we say that users are the weakest link, but this is no longer true; now, the weakest link is whatever LLM your company is using to act as both a gatekeeper and an oracle for all their users to interact with. I have two issues with enterprise LLM adoption that I want to highlight. 1) The nondeterministic nature of agents means that you can’t t... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Language Models Cannot Make Art</title><link href="/posts/Language-models-cannot-make-art/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Language Models Cannot Make Art" /><published>2026-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2026-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/Language-models-cannot-make-art/</id> <content src="/posts/Language-models-cannot-make-art/" /> <author> <name>Matt Culbert</name> </author> <summary> I was in a random coffee shop a few months back and I noticed that they had little “coffee table” books for sale. One that caught my eye was a Japanese color combination dictionary, originally printed in 1934 and reprinted and translated over the years. A combination that I found particularly nice was this one pictured below; scarlet, white, and pistachio green. In “The Art Of Doing Science ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Human Learning Is Irreplaceable</title><link href="/posts/Human-Learning-Is-Irreplaceable/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Human Learning Is Irreplaceable" /><published>2025-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2025-10-09T14:38:00+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/Human-Learning-Is-Irreplaceable/</id> <content src="/posts/Human-Learning-Is-Irreplaceable/" /> <author> <name>Matt Culbert</name> </author> <summary> What we call “AI” is really just a cancer attacking our ability to learn and we have very little time remaining to carve it out. A note When I began writing this, it was June in Vermont and one of the hottest summers we’ve had. Some towns reported a heat index of 120 Fahrenheit. Now, it’s October, and the temperature outside is 87. In October, in Vermont. To say that climate change is happen... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Building A Detection Lab Around Suricata</title><link href="/posts/Building-A-Detection-Lab-Around-Suricata/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building A Detection Lab Around Suricata" /><published>2024-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2025-09-10T18:08:10+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/Building-A-Detection-Lab-Around-Suricata/</id> <content src="/posts/Building-A-Detection-Lab-Around-Suricata/" /> <author> <name>Matt Culbert</name> </author> <summary> Building A Detection Lab Around Suricata A while back there were a flurry of posts from different people about how they were configuring their homelabs, rebuilding them to do X better than something else normally used, and automating this and that. My interest was piqued since I hadn’t played around with my equipment in a while, so I started writing up a post of my own in order to join the f... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Making Red Teaming Safer</title><link href="/posts/Making-Red-Teaming-Safer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Red Teaming Safer" /><published>2024-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2026-02-23T16:16:11+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/Making-Red-Teaming-Safer/</id> <content src="/posts/Making-Red-Teaming-Safer/" /> <author> <name>Matt Culbert</name> </author> <summary> I have been quietly hard at work the past few months turning an old project that didn’t quite work even half the time into a framework that provides the solid base of functionality required to build something much larger off of. But first, some background. Last year, I made a post about designing a red team framework. It was the offshoot of a Vault 7 project I made in Python and the first one... </summary> </entry> </feed>
